Matthew Suttie

Github: github.com/ChronoLogic12 Website: matthewsuttie.com email: msuttie12@hotmail.com

Mobile: 07908147256

Junior Web Developer

I am an aspiring web developer and have recently completed a level 5 NVQ in web app development with Code Institute and am currently looking for my first role in the industry. After independently studying coding though Codecademy and finding it engaging and fulfilling I decided in 2021 to pursue web development as a career. I have since completed several projects both front end and full stack which can be viewed via my portfolio website. With almost 8 years of experience in specialised, customer facing roles in retail environments I am highly capable with regards to communication and working as part of a team. In addition to my understanding of programming languages and frameworks I am proficient with Adobe Photoshop and XD and have aided other developers with overall website design and graphics for their projects.

Technical Skill Set

Technologies

- JavaScript
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Python

Databases

- MongoDB
- MySQL

Frameworks / Libraries

- Django
- Flask
- jQuery
- Materialize
- Bootstrap

Version Control

- Git
- Github

Professional Experience

Greenlawns Kennels Web & Graphic Designer

2020

It was my responsibility to create wireframes, both low-fidelity and high-fidelity and to create any required graphical elements for the site. These elements included backgrounds, logos and images. Throughout the project I worked directly with the web developer, consulting on the designs, graphics, colours and layouts.

- Design page layouts, colour schemes and use of graphics.
- Design/create all custom graphics and help source 3rd party icons and images.
- Edit images provided by the client for use within the site.
- Consulting with the lead web developer.

Technologies

- Adobe XD.
- Adobe Photoshop.

Waitrose and Partners Fruit, Veg and Horticulture Specialist

2015 - 2021

As a specialist my role revolved around the management, training and promotion of the fresh produce sections of the store. This involved customer service and advice, partner (employee) training, stock management and conducting quality

and legality checks.

In this role I would engage with customers in order to improve their retail experience and to promote the company's impressive range and quality of products through use of specialist knowledge and customer service skills. I would also be responsible for the training of new partners in company procedures and processes, customer service skills and product knowledge.

- Customer Service.
- Self learning/specialist knowledge. Expand and maintain product and service knowledge.
- Stock management. Checking correct stock values, sales numbers and adjusting demand via digital systems.
- Partner training.

Ceritech Audio 2013 – 2015

AV Sales Consultant

In this role I would design and sell custom audiovisual solutions to customers based on their individual requirements. These solutions would range from high end Hi-Fi and home cinema systems to multiroom audio networks and would often involve detailed product demonstrations and home installation. As part of these tasks I was required to have and maintain a large amount of detailed product knowledge and a high level of customer service skills.

- Create audiovisual solutions for customers based on requirement and budget.
- Installation, configuration and demonstration of digital systems for clients.
- Work with others in the team. Draw upon the expertise of other team members where relevant to ensure customers
 receive an ideal outcome.
- Meet and learn from suppliers to expand both specific product knowledge and knowledge of industry standards.

Education and Training

Education:

2021-2022 Code institute - Level 5 NVQ - Diploma in Web App Development

2018-2019 Waitrose - Internal qualification - Customer service / Fruit, Veg and Horticulture Specialist

2015 Ceritech Audio - Level 2 NVQ - Customer service

A Levels Music technology, Music, Physics, Biology

GCSE 11 of grade C or above including Maths and English

Technical Courses Completed:

2019+ Codecademy Javascript, C#, CSS, SCSS, RegEx and others.

Interests/Additional information

- Participation in Code Institute Hackathon: Pride: Light Up 2nd place!
- I am a passionate musician and play the flute (grade 7) and guitar to a high standard as well as several other instruments.
- I am an avid boulderer and particularly enjoy the combination of problem solving with both strength and flexibility training.
- Reading
- Full Drivers License

References are available upon request.